Finding Aid for Yale Kamisar Papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Yale Kamisar papers
1955-2010
1965-2004
Kamisar, Yale.
0596 Aa 2
Yale Kamisar, the Clarence Darrow Distinguished University Professor, was a professor in the University of Michigan Law School from 1965 to 2004. An expert in criminal law, particularly the exclusionary rule of the Fourth Amendment and the Miranda right based on the Fifth Amendment, Kamisar was a proponent of defendant rights, and wrote extensively on the subject. In the 1960s, his arguments were influential as Chief Justice Earl Warren's Supreme Court ruled on several key defendants' rights issues, such as search and seizure (Mapp v. Ohio), guaranteed legal counsel to the poor (Gideon v. Wainwright), the right to counsel while in custody (Escobedo v. Illinois), and the right to remain silent (Miranda v. Arizona). Kamisar also wrote and lectured extensively on assisted suicide, euthanasia, and mercy killing. His collection consists of research topical files; speech, debate, lecture, and presentation files; teaching files; and writings.
28 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The papers were donated to the library by Yale Kamisar (Donor no. 9579 ) beginning in March 2005. An addition was made in 2012.
The collection is open to research without restriction.
Born August 29, 1929, in East Bronx, Yale Kamisar was the child of immigrant Jewish parents, Samuel and Mollie (Levine) Kamisar. Showing early promise in art, he attended the prestigious High School of Music and Art in New York City. Kamisar won an academic scholarship to New York University, graduating in 1950. He then attended Columbia Law School. Then the Korean War intervened. He enlisted in the army. Distinguishing himself as the commander of a platoon in the assault on T-Bone Hill, Kamisar earned a Purple Heart. He returned to law school in 1952, graduating with a L.L.B. in 1954.
In 1955, Kamisar began his law career as an associate in the prestigious firm of Covington and Burling in Washington, D.C. There, he practiced anti-trust law. In 1956, in one of the few times he was in the courtroom, he represented (pro bono) a convicted drug user, who was appealing his conviction. Kamisar was appalled, when federal prosecutors attempted to use statements (which they believed to be incriminating) from the man's barely literate, hand-written petition, against his client. His impassioned statements in the courtroom won the client his appeal. This and other experiences however, convinced Kamisar that he was better-suited for the classroom.
He began his teaching career, in 1957, as an associate professor at the University of Minnesota Law School. In 1959 he was promoted to full professor. He left Minnesota in 1964 to be a visiting professor at Harvard University Law School. In 1965 Kamisar came to Ann Arbor as a professor in the University of Michigan Law School. In 1979 he was named the Henry K. Ransom Professor, a title that he retained until 1992. That year Kamisar was named the Clarence Darrow Distinguished University Professor. While at Michigan, he taught courses in Constitutional Law, Criminal Justice, Criminal Law, and Evidence.
Several decisions handed down by Justice Earl Warren's Supreme Court rendered criminal law a hot topic and with it, Yale Kamisar. These decisions included Mapp v. Ohio (1961), which prevented prosecutors from using evidence gathered in violation of the Fourth Amendment protection against unreasonable search and seizure; Gideon v. Wainwright (1963), guaranteeing that states must provide legal counsel (at least in felony cases) to defendants who could not afford to hire their own; Escobedo v. Illinois (1964), which established the defendant's right to legal counsel while in custody; and Miranda v. Arizona (1966), requiring police to inform a defendant of his right, according to the Fifth Amendment, to remain silent. All these cases had been championed by Kamisar in his earlier writings. In 1965, he wrote an article entitled "Equal Justice in the Gatehouses and Mansions of American Criminal Procedure." Often quoted by Time and other popular publications, it was critical of the free hand that was wielded by police interrogators, asking why the constitution required so much in courtrooms (mansions), but meant so little in police stations (gatehouses). The justices cited this article, and other Kamisar work, in their opinions on the Gideon and Miranda decisions. Kamisar also worked closely with the defending attorneys in the Gideon, Escobedo, and Miranda cases.
These cases were celebrated by civil libertarians but condemned by conservatives. Kamisar became a leader in the defense of the Warren court's rulings. While Miranda and the exclusionary rule have been somewhat weakened by rulings of the Burger and Rehnquist Courts, Kamisar stands as an obstacle to their total reversal.
Kamisar authored several prominent casebooks including Constitutional Law: Cases, Comments, and Questions with William B. Lockhart and Jesse H. Choper and Modern Criminal Procedure: Cases and Commentaries with Wayne R. LaFave and Jerold H. Israel. In 1958, Kamisar wrote an article entitled "Some Non-Religious Views Against Proposed 'Mercy-Killing' Legislation." This research interest was resumed in the mid-1970s, after the controversies surrounding Karen Ann Quinlan, Elizabeth Bouvia, and Sunny Von Bulow.
Kamisar presented many lectures at leading law schools, including the Mitchell Lecture at the State University of New York in Buffalo in 1977 and the Marks Memorial Lecture at the University of Arizona Law School in 1990. In 1978 Kamisar received an L.L.D honorary degrees from John Jay College of Criminal Justice, City University of New York, and an honorary degree from the University of Puget Sound in 1979. He was named Lee Distinguished Professor at the College of William and Mary for the 1987-1988 academic year. In 1990, he was cited by the National Law Journal as one of the hundred most influential lawyers in the country.
In 2002, Kamisar began to plan for his retirement from the University of Michigan and accepted a position, as professor of law, at the University of San Diego Law School. He officially retired from the University of Michigan at the end of the fall term in 2003.
Kamisar married Esther Englander on September 7, 1953. They had three sons, David, Gordon, and Jonathan. They divorced in 1973. Kamisar married Christine Keller in 1974. She died on June 12, 1997. Kamisar married Joan Russell, in February 1999.
The Yale Kamisar papers include biographical information, topical files, correspondence with law school colleagues, Supreme Court justices, judges, lawyers, and students. They also include teaching files and articles on constitutional and criminal law, particularly the exclusionary rule and the Miranda rule, as well as material on Kamisar’s work on assisted suicide, euthanasia, and mercy-killing and other topics. The papers are divided into four series: Research Topical Files; Speech, Debate, Lecture, and Presentation Files; Teaching Files; and Writings.
Subjects:
Kamisar, Yale.; Law--Study and teaching--Michigan.; University of Michigan--Law School.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; Criminal law--United States.; Exclusionary rule (Evidence)--United States.; Self-incrimination--United States--History.; Police questioning--United States.; Euthanasia.; Euthanasia--Law and legislation.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Kamisar, Yale.; Urban, Otto.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Videotapes.
- Research Topical Files, 2003-2004; 14. 4 linear feet
  Research Topical Files series (14. 4 linear feet), covering the period from 1955 to 2004, documents Kamisar's standing in the legal and academic communities throughout the United States. The files were received in two accessions, but in fact represent a single run of files kept over his career.
  The Research Files include correspondence with Supreme Court justices, colleagues, judges, students, editors of law reviews, and publishers; articles by Kamisar and others, describing and arguing various cases and topics; Supreme Court and other judicial opinions and legal precedents; news clippings and op-ed pieces commenting on many aspects of legal opinion; and biographical information, including photographs. The original filing order was maintained. In most cases, Kamisar's secretarial staff used acronyms when filing, so the American Bar Association will be found under ABA and the Bureau of National Affairs will be found under BNA, though researchers should also consult the full name of the organization as well. His original folders were maintained, whenever possible, so that any notes Kamisar made on the folders are available for researchers. These include cross references which will aid in locating related material in the Research Topical Files series.
  Two principal areas of research interest for Kamisar are patient rights and defendant rights (Exclusionary rule of the Fourth Amendment and the Miranda warning, guaranteed by the Fifth Amendment). This series includes strong coverage of the protection of the rights of criminal defendants. The researcher will find multiple folders under the headings Confessions, Constitutional Law, Criminal Law, Death Penalty, Drugs, and the Supreme Court. Early in his career, Kamisar became interested in patient rights as they pertain to criminal law, in such areas as assisted suicide, euthanasia, and mercy-killing. There are multiple folders relating to these topics in this series, including Euthanasia (with folders discussing the cases of Baby Jane Doe, Paul Brophy, children, Medical Economics, and Karen Ann Quinlan's guardians) and Suicide (folders on assisted suicide and the Elizabeth Bouvia case). For more material on these subjects, researchers should consult folders in the Speeches Files, and Teaching Files under the heading "Criminal Law." In his Writings Files, researchers will find the 1958 article, published in the University of Minnesota Law Review, entitled "Some Non-Religious Views Against Proposed 'Mercy-Killing' Legislation" and another copy with a forward from 1973.
  Photographs of Kamisar can be found under Biography-Miscellaneous (Box 2) and Photographs (Box 12) and Vita (box 14),. There is also a photograph of Baltimore police chief Otto Urban (box 14).
  - A-B
    - AALS, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
    - ABA (American Bar Association)
      - Criminal Justice, 1988; undated (Box 1)
      - Human Rights, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
      - Individual Rights, 1983 (Box 1)
      - Journal, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
      - Meetings
        - July, 1982 (Box 1)
        - 1988-1997 (Box 1)
        - 1996 (Box 1)
    - ABC
      - General, 1981-1993 (Box 1)
      - Oberman, Jim, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Abraham, Gerald, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Abrams, Floyd, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Abramson, Jeffrey, 1996; undated (Box 1)
    - ABSCAM, 1980-1983 (Box 1)
    - Acknowledgments, 1980 (Box 1)
    - ACLU (American Civil Liberties Union)
      - 1983-1993 (Box 1)
      - Canada, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Activities and Publications, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
    - Adler, Joel, 1985-1991 (Box 1)
    - Adler, Mitchell, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Admissions Data, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Advertising
      - New York Times, 1991 (Box 1)
      - University of Michigan Press, 1979-1981 (Box 1)
      - West Publishing Company, 1974-1997 (Box 1)
    - Advocates, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Affirmative Action, 1987-1996 (Box 1)
    - Agee Case, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Ahronheim, Judith, 1990; 1993 (Box 1)
    - AIDS, 1988-1996 (Box 1)
    - Aigler, William F., 1983 (Box 1)
    - Alaska Bar Trip, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - Alexander, George, undated (Box 1)
    - Aliens, 1981-1986 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Francis A., 1960-1994 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Ron
      - 1974-1998 (Box 1)
      - American Law Institute, 1979-1985 (Box 1)
    - Alschuler, Albert W., 1985-1996 (Box 1)
    - Alumni, 1980-1993 (Box 1)
    - Amar, Akhil, 1993 (Box 1)
    - American Association of Attorney-Certified Public Accountants, 1991 (Box 1)
    - American Bar Association (See also ABA), 1995 (Box 1)
    - American Criminal Law Review, 1980-1991 (Box 1)
    - American Judicature Society, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
    - American Law Institute, 1997 (Box 1)
    - The American Lawyer (includes cassette tape of Biron Confession), 1990 (Box 1)
    - American Lawyer Newspaper Group, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
    - Amsterdam, Anthony, 1981-1983 (Box 1)
    - Anderson, Laura, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Anderson Publishing Company, 1991; 1995 (Box 1)
    - Ann Arbor News, 1989; 1997; undated (Box 1)
    - Annas, George, 1993; 1996 (Box 1)
    - Annual Memos, 1988-1992 (Box 1)
    - Annual Report-Tenured Faculty, 1991-2004 (Box 1)
    - Areen, Judith, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Arenella, Peter, 1982-1997 (Box 1)
    - Ares, Charles E., 1981 (Box 1)
    - Arguments, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Arizona, University of, 1989-1994 (Box 1)
    - Arkin, Marc, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Armentrout, Barbara, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Arnold, Morris, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Arras, John, 1993-1999 (Box 1)
    - Article Inquiries (Permissions, Reprints), 1972-1976 (Box 1)
    - Asselin, Donald, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
    - Atlanta (Wayne B. Williams), 1981-1982 (Box 1)
    - Atlanta Conference (William Murphy-College of Criminal Trial Lawyers), 1976 (Box 1)
    - Attica, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Audio Visual, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Automobile Search, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Averbrook, Charles J., 1971-1983 (Box 1)
    - Baier, Paul, 1983-1991 (Box 2)
    - Bailey, Ronald Lloyd, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
    - Baker, Liva, 1981-1984 (Box 2)
    - Bakke
      - General, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
      - University of Michigan Law School, 1978 (Box 2)
    - Baldus, David, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Baltimore Sun, 1982; 1986 (Box 2)
    - Ban, Michael, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Bandes, Susan (ACLU), 1984-1985 (Box 2)
    - Bar Exam Questions and Model Answers, 1991-1994 (Box 2)
    - Barker, Robert, 1983 (Box 2)
    - Baron, Charles, 1993-1997 (Box 2)
    - Barnett, Martha W., 1982 (Box 2)
    - Barrett, Ed, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Barristers, 1987; 1989 (Box 2)
    - Barry, Robert, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Bartels, Robert, 1983-1986 (Box 2)
    - Bartosic, Florian, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Bator, Paul, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Baude, Patrick, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
    - Baum Lectures, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Bazelon, David L., 1979-1985; 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Beale, Sara, 1984-2000 (Box 2)
    - Beaney, William, 1960 (Box 2)
    - Beauchamp, Tom L. (Georgetown University), 1989-1990 (Box 2)
    - Bechstein, Erika, 1971; 1975 (Box 2)
    - Beck, June undated (Box 2)
    - Becker, Edward R., 1981-1982 (Box 2)
    - Becker, Robert, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Beckman, Sharon, 1984-1996 (Box 2)
    - Beiser, Edwin [sic Edward], 1988; 1991 (Box 2)
    - Belin, David, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Bender, Paul, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Bendix Corporation, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Benner, Laurence A., 1989 (Box 2)
    - Bennett, Robert W., 1985-1986 (Box 2)
    - Berger, Vivian, 1984-1988 (Box 2)
    - Bernardin, Cardinal Joseph, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Bernstein, Bob, 1980; 1985 (Box 2)
    - Beytagh, Francis X., 1962; undated (Box 2)
    - Bibliography, 1973-1977 (Box 2)
    - Bickel, Alexander M., 1963-1964 (Box 2)
    - Bierbower, James, 1957-1983 (Box 2)
    - Bihary, Sheila, 1977-1982 (Box 2)
    - Bill of Rights, 1987-1993 (Box 2)
    - Biography
      - Articles about Kamisar, 1974-1977 (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous (includes photograph of Kamisar), undated (Box 2)
      - Publications (bibliography), 1966-1986 (Box 2)
    - Bird, Rose Elizabeth, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Black, Barbara A., 1986; undated (Box 2)
    - Blackmun, Harry A., 1984-1994 (Box 2)
    - Blacks, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
    - Bladel and Jackson Cases, 1985 (Box 2)
    - Blake, Harlan, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Blakey, Robert, 1983-1995; undated (Box 2)
    - Blasi, Vince, 1983-1988 (Box 2)
    - Bloch, Susan (includes cassette tape), 1983-1995 (Box 2)
    - Bloom, Robert M., 1985 (Box 2)
    - Blurbs, 1993 (Box 2)
    - BNA (Bureau of National Affairs)
      - Advertising, 1981-1985; undated (Box 2)
      - Correspondence and Terms, 1987-1997 (Box 2)
      - General, 1995-1997; 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Boettcher, Gordon, 1983 (Box 2)
    - Boggan, E. Carrington, 1981; 1989 (Box 2)
    - Bok, Derek, 1983 (Box 2)
    - Bollinger, Lee, 1987-2001 (Box 2)
    - Book Reviews, 1979-1996; undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Bork, Robert H., 1987-1988 (Box 2)
    - Bork and Dorsen, 1982-1983; undated (Box 2)
    - Boshhoff, Douglass, 1987-1990 (Box 2)
    - Boston Globe, 1993-1996; undated (Box 2)
    - Boston (Stuart, Carol and Charles), 1990 (Box 2)
    - Bostrom, Barry, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Boudin, Leonard B., 1983 (Box 2)
    - Bowers v. Hardwick, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Boylan, Roger, undated (Box 2)
    - Bracken, Edward, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Bradley, Craig M., 1982-1997 (Box 3)
    - Braeman, John, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Brandeis, Louis D., 1982; 1991 (Box 3)
    - Branton, Leo, Jr., 1986 (Box 3)
    - Brawley Case, 1988 (Box 3)
    - Brecht, Albert, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Brennan, William, 1962; 1985-1990 (Box 3)
    - Brereton, Bonnie, 1989 (Box 3)
    - Breslin, Ed, 1989 (Box 3)
    - Brest, Paul A., undated (Box 3)
    - The Brethern (Bob Woodward), 1979-1980 (Box 3)
    - Brewer v. Williams, 1977 (Box 3)
    - Bright, Myron, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Brill, Steven, 1991 (Box 3)
    - Brilmayer, Lea, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Brown, Betty, undated (Box 3)
    - Brown v. Board of Education, 1984 (Box 3)
    - Brownmiller, Susan, 1989 (Box 3)
    - Brubaker, Stanley C., 1985 (Box 3)
    - Burger and Warren Courts, 1979-1986 (Box 3)
    - Burglary, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Burke, Ed, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
    - Burkoff, John M., 1981-1994 (Box 3)
    - Burn Center, 1977 (Box 3)
    - Burnham, 1992 (Box 3)
    - Burr, Richard B., 1991-1993 (Box 3)
  - C-D
    - Caldwell, Arthur B., 1962-1963 (Box 3)
    - California
      - Bar, 1992-1995 (Box 3)
      - Legislature, 1980 (Box 3)
      - Supreme Court, 1984 (Box 3)
      - University of California-Davis, 1989 (Box 3)
    - Callahan, Daniel, 1993-1998 (Box 3)
    - Cambridge University Press, 1995-1997 (Box 3)
    - Cameras, 1987 (Box 3)
    - Campbell Board, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
    - Canada, 1982; 1987 (Box 3)
    - Canon, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
    - Cantor, Norman L., 1990-1998 (Box 3)
    - Capital Punishment, undated (Box 3)
    - Caplan, Arthur, 1991-1995 (Box 3)
    - Caplan, Gerald M., 1965-1994 (Box 3)
    - Capron, Alexander, 1992-1994 (Box 3)
    - Car and Driver Magazine, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
    - Carlson, Ronald L., 1986 (Box 3)
    - Carrington, Frank, 1981-1988 (Box 3)
    - Carrington Paul D., 1974-1997 (Box 3)
    - Carter, James Earl, 1978 (Box 3)
    - Cartoons, 1983; undated (Box 3)
    - Case Western Reserve, 1979; 1991 (Box 3)
    - Caseclub, 1980; 1988 (Box 3)
    - Casper Star Tribune, 1989 (Box 3)
    - Catchot, Dianne, 1995 (Box 3)
    - CBS, 1980-1990 (Box 3)
    - Celler, Emanuel, 1959-1960 (Box 3)
    - Chamberlain, Laura A., 1994 (Box 3)
    - Chambers Trial, 1988 (Box 3)
    - The Champion, 1991 (Box 3)
    - Chandler v. Florida, 1981-1984 (Box 3)
    - Chase, Mrs. Harold (Bernice), 1982 (Box 3)
    - Chase, Harold, 1963-1981 (Box 3)
    - Chicago Tribune, 1992-1997 (Box 3)
    - Child Abuse, 1978-1989 (Box 3)
    - Child and Family, 1987-1990 (Box 3)
    - Children's Rights, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Choper, Jesse H., 1987-1996 (Box 3)
    - Christian Science Monitor, 1990-1996 (Box 3)
    - Christie, C. V., Jr., 1979-1990 (Box 3)
    - Christmas Card List, undated (Box 3)
    - Christmas Creche Issue, 1987 (Box 3)
    - Christmas Play, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Church and State, 1964-1982 (Box 3)
    - Class Assignments, 1996-1997 (Box 3)
    - Cleveland, City of, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Clifford, Robert L., 1989 (Box 3)
    - Codner, Fred G., 1986; undated (Box 3)
    - Coffin, Frank M., 1983-1987 (Box 3)
    - Cohen, Carl, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Cohen, Fred, 1985-1992 (Box 3)
    - Cohen, Herbert, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Cohen, William, 1959-1986 (Box 3)
    - Cohn, Avern, 1986-1997 (Box 3)
    - Colb, Sherry, F., 1993 (Box 4)
    - Collection of Leading Cases, 1982 (Box 4)
    - Collette, Charles T., 1990 (Box 4)
    - Collins, Ron, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Columbia
      - 1983-1998 (Box 4)
      - Class Reunion, 1989 (Box 4)
      - Columbia Law Review, 1989 (Box 4)
    - Comparative Study (Exclusionary Rule), 1981-1982 (Box 4)
    - Confessions
      - 1966-1994, 2 folders (Box 4)
      - Police Interrogation and Confessions, 1982 (Box 4)
      - Tapes, 1981 (Box 4)
    - Conolly, Matthew, 1983-1986 (Box 4)
    - Conspiracy, 1974 (Box 4)
    - Constitutional Law
      - 1970-1998, 8 folders (Box 4)
      - Bicentennial, 1987 (Box 4)
      - Budget, 1986 (Box 4)
      - Class Materials, 1980 (Box 4)
      - Editions
        - Fifth, 1976 (Box 4)
        - Sixth (Revisions), 1984 (Box 4)
      - Supplements, 1984; 1993; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Constitutional Rights (State), 1984 (Box 4)
    - Cook, Julian Abele, 1985 (Box 4)
    - Cook County Public Defender, 1990 (Box 4)
    - Cooley Lectures, 1971-1994 (Box 4)
    - Coombs, Mary, 1990-1993 (Box 4)
    - Coppola, Frank J., 1982 (Box 4)
    - Cornell Law Review, 1999 (Box 4)
    - Cornwell, Yeates, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1988-1994; 3 folders (Box 4)
      - Personal, 1975-1992 (Box 4)
    - Corrigan, Maura (Crane), 1992 (Box 4)
    - Covington and Burling, 1986; 1999 (Box 4)
    - Cowley, Rob, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Cramton, Roger, 1984-1991 (Box 4)
    - Craver, Charles B., 1984 (Box 4)
    - Creighton University
      - Mailing, 1983 (Box 4)
      - Reprints, 1983 (Box 4)
    - Criminal Insanity, 1980 (Box 4)
    - Criminal Justice Procedure, 1985 (Box 4)
    - Criminal Justice Programs Office, 1979-1980 (Box 4)
    - Criminal Justice Weekly, 1999 (Box 4)
    - Criminal Law, 1979-1997; 6 folders (Box 4)
    - Criminal Law Bulletin, 1978-1989 (Box 5)
    - Criminal Law Forum, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Criminal Procedure Casebook, 1980-1981; undated (Box 5)
    - Criminal Procedure Supplement
      - 1989-1998 (Box 5)
      - Japanese, 1985 (Box 5)
      - Sixth Edition, 1982 (Box 5)
    - Croson Decision, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Crump, David, 1984-1985 (Box 5)
    - Cruzan, Nancy, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
    - C-Span, 1992-1993 (Box 5)
    - Curfew, 1983-1989 (Box 5)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1992 (Box 5)
    - Curtis, Charlotte, 1979 (Box 5)
    - Custody, 1973-1993 (Box 5)
    - Darrow, Clarence (Distinguished University Professor), 1992; undated (Box 5)
    - David, Marcella, 1990-1995 (Box 5)
    - Davies, Thomas Y., 1983-1995 (Box 5)
    - Davis, Edward P., 1983 (Box 5)
    - Davis, Morton, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
    - D.C. (Washington) Circuit 51st Judicial Conference, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
    - Deanships, 1984; 1986 (Box 5)
    - Deason, Ellen, 1987 (Box 5)
    - Death Penalty
      - General, 1976-1988; 4 folders (Box 5)
      - Child, 1986 (Box 5)
    - Debating Team (University of Michigan), 1985-1991 (Box 5)
    - Dellinger, Walter, 1982-1984 (Box 5)
    - Demjanjuk Episode, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Dennis, James L, 1982 (Box 5)
    - Department Memos/Activities, 1978 (Box 5)
    - Dershowitz, Alan M., 1982-1992 (Box 5)
    - Detroit College of Law Review, 1983 (Box 5)
    - Detroit Free Press, 1980-1994 (Box 5)
    - Detroit News, 1988-2003 (Box 5)
    - Detroit, University of, 1994-1995 (Box 5)
    - Deveney, Marie, 1985 (Box 5)
    - Dewey, Alvin A., 1966 (Box 5)
    - Dictionary of American History, 1973-1975 (Box 5)
    - Dimond, Paul, 1981-1989 (Box 5)
    - Dinsmore, Charles B., 1989 (Box 5)
    - Disabilities, 1995 (Box 5)
    - Discrimination, 1988; 1993 (Box 5)
    - Dix, George, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Doerflinger, Richard, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Doernberg, Donald, 1983 (Box 5)
    - Dorsen, Norman, 1984-1989 (Box 5)
    - Double Jeopardy, 1988-1989 (Box 5)
    - Douglas, William O., 1975 (Box 5)
    - Doukas, David, 1990-1993 (Box 5)
    - Doyle, John H., III, 1983 (Box 5)
    - Doyle, Sean (Georgetown), 1988 (Box 5)